Inventory of the Gesamtverband Deutscher Antikommunistischer Vereinigungen records
Hoover Institution Archives
Gesamtverband Deutscher Antikommunistischer Vereinigungen records
1891-1945
XX090
Gesamtverband Deutscher Antikommunistischer Vereinigungen
227 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 4 oversize boxes (99.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, reports, and clippings, relating to the international communist movement and to Jews.
Administrative Information
Access
Microfilm use only.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Entire collection available on microfilm (258 reels).
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection of writings, reports, and clippings relating to the international communist movement and to Jews was assembled by the Gesamtverband Deutscher Antikommunistischer Vereinigungen, a German governmental anti-communist and anti-Semitic propaganda agency affiliated with the Reichsministerium für Volksaufklärung und Propaganda. It was used as an intelligence source on the communist movement worldwide, and provided fuel for the ministry's propaganda campaigns. Most of the material is in German.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series: News Clippings, Monitoring Reports, Manuscripts, and Printed Matter and Photographs.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei; Anti-communist movements--Germany; Antisemitism--Germany; National socialism; Propaganda, German; World War, 1939-1945--Germany; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda
Related Material
Reichsministerium für Volksaufklärung und Propaganda miscellaneous records, Hoover Institution Archives
Collection Contents
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Group I, News Clippings, 1891-1945; (bulk 1932-1945); (73 linear feet) (Box 1-175)
  Clippings from German newspapers and service reports.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of country, thereunder sometimes arranged by topic. German topical labels found on these files include:
  Alle Position (Alle Pos)
  Social standing
  Kultur (Kul)
  Culture
  Politik (Pol)
  Politics
  Rasse
  Race
  Siedlung (Sied)
  Settlement
  Ueberblick (Ueberb)
  Overview
  Verwaltung (Verw)
  Administration
  Wirtschaft (Wir)
  Economics
  Zeitung (Zei)
  Newspaper
  Twenty-eight boxes of unsorted material (boxes 147-171, 173-175), and one box of individually listed manuscripts (box 172), follow the material arranged by country
  - Afghanistan--Jews, 1938-1942 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Albania--Jews, 1937-1939 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Arabia--Jews, 1937-1944 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Argentina-Jews, 1936-1943 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Argentina-Jews, 1937-1941 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Argentina-Jews, 1938-1941 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Argentina-Jews, 1939-1942 (Folder 2: 2-3)
  - Argentina-Jews, 1939-1943 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Australia (Folder 3: 1-2)
  - Australia--Jews--Political conditions, 1934-1943 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Austria (Folder 3: 4)
  - Austria (Folder 4: 1-5)
  - Belgium-Jews, 1936-1942 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Belgium-Jews, 1936-1942 (Folder 5: 1)
  - Belgium-Jews, 1936-1943 (Folder 5: 2-4)
  - Belgium-Jews, 1937-1942 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Belgium-Jews, 1937-1943 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Belgium-Jews, 1938-1942 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Belgium-Jews, 1936-1943 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Bolivia--Jews, 1937-1942 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Brazil--Jews, 1936-1942 (Folder 7: 1-2)
  - Bulgaria-Jews, 1936-1942 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Bulgaria-Jews, 1937-1942 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Bulgaria-Jews, 1942-1943 (Folder 8: 1)
  - Canada (Folder 8: 2)
  - Chile--Jews, 1938-1942 (Folder 8: 3)
  - China-Jews, 1938-1940 (Folder 8: 4-5)
  - China-Jews, 1939-1941 (Folder 9: 1)
  - Colombia--Jews, 1938-1942 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Costa Rica--Jews, 1938-1941 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Cuba--Jews, 1938-1942 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 9: 5)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 10: 1-5)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 11: 1-6)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 12: 1-4)
  - Czechoslovakia, including Bohemia and Moravia (Folder 12: 5)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 13: 1-6)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 14: 1-4, Folder 14A: 5-6)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 15: 1-2)
  - Danzig--Jews--Social conditions, 1939 (Folder 15: 3-5)
  - Denmark--Jews, 1937-1943 (Folder 15: 6-8)
  - Denmark--Jews, 1937-1943 (Folder 16: 1-3)
  - Dominican Republic--Jews--Immigration, 1938-1943 (Folder 16: 4)
  - Ecuador--Jews--Social conditions, 1938 (Folder 16: 5)
  - El Salvador (Folder 16: 6)
  - Estonia--Jews--Social conditions, 1935-1941 (Folder 16A: 7)
  - Finland--Jews--Political conditions, 1938-1944 (Folder 17: 1-3)
  - Finland--Jews--Political conditions, 1939-1941 (Folder 17: 4)
  - France--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1936-1944 (Folder 17: 5-6)
  - France--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1940-1941 (Folder 18: 1-3)
  - France--Anti-Semitic propaganda, 1936-1944 (Folder 18: 4-6)
  - France--Anti-Semitic propaganda, 1941 (Folder 19: 1)
  - France--Freemasons, 1936-1942 (Folder 19: 2-3)
  - France--Freemasons, 1940-1941 (Folder 19: 4-6)
  - France--Jewish criminals, 1938-1943 (Folder 20: 1-3)
  - France--Jewish soldiers, 1938-1943 (Folder 20: 4-5)
  - France--Jews--General, 1936-1941 (Folder 20: 6-7)
  - France--Jews--Caricatures, 1938-1942 (Folder 21: 1)
  - France--Jews--Cinema, 1936-1942 (Folder 21: 2-4)
  - France--Jews--Colonies, 1937-1939 (Folder 21: 5)
  - France--Jews--Colonies, 1939-1944 (Folder 21: 6)
  - France--Jews--Deportation, 1937-1942 (Folder 21: 7)
  - France--Jews--Deportation, 1939-1942 (Folder 21: 8)
  - France--Jews--Economic conditions, 1932-1942 (Folder 22: 1-2)
  - France--Jews--Economic conditions, 1934-1942 (Folder 22: 3)
  - France--Jews--Economic conditions, 1937-1940 (Folder 22: 4)
  - France--Jews--Economic conditions, 1938-1939 (Folder 22: 5)
  - France--Jews--Education, 1938-1942 (Folder 22: 6)
  - France--Jews--Emigration to Madagascar, 1940 (Folder 22: 7)
  - France--Jews--History, 1932-1942 (Folder 23: 1)
  - France--Jews--History, 1937-1944 (Folder 23: 2-3)
  - France--Jews--Journalism, 1937-1939 (Folder 23: 4)
  - France--Jews--Journalism, 1937-1941 (Folder 23: 5-6)
  - France--Jews--Journalism, 1938-1940 (Folder 23: 7-8)
  - France--Jews--Journalism, 1938-1942 (Folder 24: 1-3)
  - France--Jews--Law, 1940-1942 (Folder 24: 4)
  - France--Jews--Medicine, 1936-1942 (Folder 24: 5-6)
  - France--Jews--Political conditions, 1936-1939 (Folder 24: 7)
  - France--Jews--Political conditions, 1938-1940 (Folder 25: 1-3)
  - France--Jews--Political conditions, 1938-1941 (Folder 25: 4, Folder 25A: 5-6)
  - France--Jews--Political conditions, 1938-1942 (Folder 26: 1-4)
  - France--Jews--Political conditions, 1942-1944 (Folder 26: 5-8)
  - France--Jews--Political conditions, 1942-1944 (Folder 27: 1-2)
  - France--Jews--Radio, 1938-1940 (Folder 27: 3)
  - France--Jews--Social conditions, 1934-1938 (Folder 27: 4, Folder 27A: 5-7)
  - France--Jews--Social conditions, 1938-1940 (Folder 28: 1-4)
  - France--Jews--Social conditions, 1942-1944 (Folder 28: 5-6)
  - France--Jews--Statistics, 1939-1942 (Folder 29: 1-2)
  - France--Jews--Theater, 1939-1942 (Folder 29: 3)
  - France--Jews--Universities, 1935-1943 (Folder 29: 4-5)
  - France--Jews in Corsica, 1938-1942 (Folder 29: 6)
  - France--Political conditions, 1938-1941 (Folder 29: 7-10)
  - France--Political conditions, 1938-1941 (Folder 30: 1-5)
  - France--Political conditions, 1938-1942 (Folder 31: 1-4)
  - France--Political conditions, 1942 (Folder 31: 5-6)
  - France--Racial questions, 1937-1943 (Folder 31: 7-8)
  - France--Religion, 1938-1942 (Folder 32: 1-2)
  - Germany--Anti-communist propaganda, 1936-1939 (Folder 32: 3)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1935-1938 (Folder 32: 4-6)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1935-1940 (Folder 33: 1-6)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1935-1940 (Folder 34: 1-3)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1935-1941 (Folder 34: 4-7)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1936-1939 (Folder 35: 1-5)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1936-1939 (Folder 35: 1-5)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1937-1939 (Folder 35: 6-7)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1937-1943 (Folder 36: 1-3)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1938 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1938-1939 (Folder 36: 5-6)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1938-1942 (Folder 36: 7)
  - Germany--Anti-Semitic legislation, 1939-1941 (Folder 36: 8)
  - Germany--Colonies, 1938-1940 (Folder 37: 1)
  - Germany--Foreign relations--Great Britain, see Great Britain--Foreign relations--Germany
  - Germany--Freemasons, 1927-1938 (Folder 37: 2)
  - Germany--Jewish criminals, 1934-1939 (Folder 37: 3-5)
  - Germany--Jewish criminals, 1934-1940 (Folder 37: 6-7)
  - Germany--Jewish criminals, 1937-1939 (Folder 38: 1-4)
  - Germany--Jewish cultural organizations, 1934-1938 (Folder 38: 5-7)
  - Germany--Jewish cultural organizations, 1935-1939 (Folder 39: 1)
  - Germany--Jewish cultural organizations, 1935-1939 (Folder 39: 2-4)
  - Germany--Jewish cultural organizations, 1941-1943 (Folder 39: 5-6)
  - Germany--Jewish physicians, 1934-1939 (Folder 39: 7-8)
  - Germany--Jewish physicians, 1934-1939 (Folder 40: 1-2)
  - Germany--Jewish students, 1936-1939 (Folder 40: 3-8)
  - Germany--Jewish students, 1937-1943 (Folder 41: 1-4)
  - Germany--Jewish welfare organizations, 1937-1938 (Folder 41: 5)
  - Germany--Jews--General, 1891-1941 (Folder 41: 6-9)
  - Germany--Jews--Book reviews, 1936-1944 (Folder 42: 1-4)
  - Germany--Jews--Deportation, 1937-1942 (Folder 42: 5)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1934-1941 (Folder 42: 6-9)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1934-1941 (Folder 43: 1)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1934-1943 (Folder 43: 2-5)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1937-1939 (Folder 43: 6-9)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1937-1939 (Folder 44: 1-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1937-1939 (Folder 45: 1-6)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1938-1939 (Folder 45: 7-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1938-1939 (Folder 46: 1-7)
  - Germany--Jews--Economic conditions, 1938-1939 (Folder 47: 1-7)
  - Germany--Jews--Emigration, 1934-1939 (Folder 48: 1-4)
  - Germany--Jews--Emigration, 1935-1941 (Folder 48: 5-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Emigration, 1938-1939 (Folder 49: 1-5)
  - Germany--Jews--Film, 1936-1943 (Folder 49: 6-9)
  - Germany--Jews--Genealogy, 1936-1941 (Folder 50: 1-3)
  - Germany--Jews--History, 1914-1938 (Folder 50: 4-7)
  - Germany--Jews--History, 1914-1938 (Folder 51: 1-6)
  - Germany--Jews--History, 1918-1941 (Folder 51: 7-11)
  - Germany--Jews--Journalism, 1936-1943 (Folder 52: 1-2)
  - Germany--Jews--Kristallnacht, 1938 (Folder 52: 3-5)
  - Germany--Jews--Law, 1934-1943 (Folder 52: 6-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Music, 1936-1943 (Folder 52: 9-10)
  - Germany--Jews--Political conditions, 1935-1939 (Folder 53: 1-5)
  - Germany--Jews--Political conditions, 1938 (Folder 53: 6-7)
  - Germany--Jews--Political conditions, 1938 (Folder 54: 1-3)
  - Germany--Jews--Political conditions, 1938-1939 (Folder 54: 4-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Political conditions, 1935-1939 (Folder 55: 1-5)
  - Germany--Jews--Political conditions, 1938-1943 (Folder 55: 6-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Radio, 1936-1943 (Folder 55: 9)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1933-1938 (Folder 56: 1-5)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1934-1938 (Folder 56: 6-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1934-1940 (Folder 57: 1-4)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1934-1942 (Folder 57: 5-8)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1936-1938 (Folder 58: 1-3)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1936-1943 (Folder 58: 4-6)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1937-1939 (Folder 58: 7-10)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1937-1939 (Folder 59: 1-3)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1938-1939 (Folder 59: 4-10)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1938-1941 (Folder 60: 1-3)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--General, 1939-1943 (Folder 60: 4-7)
  - Germany--Jews--Social conditions--Berlin, 1935-1939 (Folder 60: 8-10)
  - Germany--Jews--Statistics, 1933-1943 (Folder 61: 1-7)
  - Germany--Jews--Theater, 1936-1941 (Folder 61: 8-10)
  - Germany--Jews--Zionism, 1937-1939 (Folder 62: 1-3)
  - Germany--Jews in Reichsprotektorat Böhmen und Mãhren (Bohemia and Moravia), 1938-1940 (Folder 62: 4-6)
  - Germany--Politics and government, 1933-1945 (Folder 62: 7)
  - Germany--Race questions, 1937-1942 (Folder 62: 8-12)
  - Great Britain--Anti-Semitism, 1939-1943 (Folder 63: 1-4)
  - Great Britain--Colonies, 1939-1942 (Folder 63: 5)
  - Great Britain--Communists, 1936-1943 (Folder 63: 6-8)
  - Great Britain--Foreign relations--Germany, 1937-1938 (Folder 63: 9-14)
  - Great Britain--Freemasons, 1936-1941 (Folder 64: 1-4)
  - Great Britain--Jewish question in Europe, 1938-1944 (Folder 64: 4-10)
  - Great Britain--Jewish question in Europe, 1941-1942 (Folder 65: 1-4)
  - Great Britain--Jewish refugees, 1936-1939 (Folder 65: 5-10)
  - Great Britain--Jews--Journalism, 1937-1939 (Folder 65: 11-13)
  - Great Britain--Jews--Political conditions, 1936-1943 (Folder 66: 1-3)
  - Great Britain--Jews--Political conditions, 1937-1939 (Folder 66: 4-10)
  - Great Britain--Jews--Political conditions, 1937-1942 (Folder 67: 1-5)
  - Great Britain--Jews--Social conditions, 1939-1943 (Folder 67: 6-8)
  - Great Britain--Jews--Social conditions, 1942-1944 (Folder 67: 9-10)
  - Great Britain--Unsorted material (Box 68-73)
  - Great Britain--Unsorted material (Folder 74: 1-5)
  - Greece--Jews--Political conditions, 1934-1942 (Folder 74: 6-8)
  - Guatemala (Folder 74: 9)
  - Hungary (Folder 74: 10-12)
  - Hungary (Box 75-79)
  - Hungary (Folder 80: 1-4)
  - India (Folder 80: 5-12)
  - India (Folder 81: 1-11)
  - Iran (Folder 82: 1-2)
  - Iraq (Folder 82: 3-5)
  - Italy (Folder 82: 6-13)
  - Italy (Box 83-88)
  - Japan (Folder 89: 1-8)
  - Latvia (Folder 89: 9-12)
  - Lithuania (Folder 90: 1-10)
  - Luxemburg (Folder 90: 11-13)
  - Mexico (Folder 91: 1-8)
  - Netherlands--Jews--Journalism, 1936-1941 (Folder 91: 9-12)
  - Netherlands--Unsorted material (Box 92-94)
  - Nicaragua (Folder 95: 1)
  - Norway--Jews, 1938-1943 (Folder 95: 2-12)
  - Palestine--Political conditions, 1938-1939 (Folder 96: 1-8)
  - Palestine--Unsorted material (Folder 96: 9-12)
  - Palestine--Unsorted material (Box 97-104)
  - Panama (Folder 105: 1)
  - Poland (Folder 105: 2-13)
  - Poland (Box 106, 106A-112)
  - Portugal (Folder 113: 1-5)
  - Romania (Folder 113: 6-14)
  - Romania (Box 114-118)
  - South Africa (Folder 119: 1-6)
  - Soviet Union (Folder 119: 7-12)
  - Soviet Union (Box 120-121)
  - Spain (Box 122)
  - Sweden (Box 123-125)
  - Sweden (Folder 126: 1-6)
  - Switzerland (Folder 126: 7-11)
  - Switzerland (Box 127-128)
  - Switzerland (Folder 129: 1-9)
  - Syria--Jews--Political conditions, 1937-1942 (Folder 129: 10-11)
  - Syria--Jews--Political conditions, 1938-1941 (Folder 129: 12-13)
  - Turkey (Folder 130: 1-4)
  - United States (Folder 130: 5-13)
  - United States (Box 131-142)
  - Uruguay (Box 143)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 144)
  - Office files and miscellany (Folder 145)
  - Miscellany (Box 146)
  - Unsorted material (Box 147-171)
  - Manuscripts (Part C), 1917-1944
    - Der Jahrhunderte alte Kampf der Slaven mit den deutschen Eroberern, von dem Akademiker N. S. Dershawin, 1943.; Ts Slavs D438 (Folder 172: 1)
    - (1) Liste grundlegender kommunistischer und prokommunistischer Gesellschaften und Organisationen, deren Tätigkeit im Ausland, d. h. ausserhalb der Sowjetunion verlief oder verläuft, (2) Liste kommunistischer und prokommunistischer Gesellschaften und Organisationen, die in dem Jahr 1937 in den einzelnen Ländern existierten, (3) Liste kommunistischer und prokommunistischer Gesellschaften und Organisationen, die gegenwärtig tätig sind, 1944; Ts Communism G389 (Folder 172: 2)
    - (1) Letter, Alexander v. Melgunoff to Reichsminister für Volksaufklärung und Propaganda Dr. Goebbels, (2) Der russische Auftrag, von Alexander v. Melgunoff, 1944.; Ts Germany M521e (Folder 172: 3)
    - Was ist UNRRA? von Prof. A. Woskressensky, 1944.; Ts UNRRA W935. Translated from Russian (Folder 172: 4)
    - Die deutsche Sendung im Osten, von Alexander v. Melgunoff, undated.; Ts Germany M521 (Folder 172: 5)
    - Der Aufstand in Kronstadt, [March 1921]; Ts Russia G389au (Folder 172: 6)
    - Die Behandlung internationaler Verträge durch die Bolschewiken, 1944.; Ts Russia G389b (Folder 172: 7)
    - Stalin geht zum Angriff über, from "Leidensjahr des esthnischen Volkes,", undated.; Ts Estonia E7 (Folder 172: 8)
    - Material über die Schreckensherrschaft der Bolschewisten in Estland, 1940-1941; 1943.; Ts Estonia G389m (Folder 172: 9)
    - Bolschewistische Wirtschaft in Estland 1940-41, Statistisches Amt für Estland, 1941.; Ts Estonia E7 R572 (Folder 172: 10)
    - Aufbau des Volkskommissariates für Innere Angelegenheiten der Sowjet-Union (NKWD), undated.; Ts Russia G389a (Folder 172: 11)
    - Gedanken zur Frage über die Schauprozesse, undated.; Ts Russia G389ae (Folder 172: 12)
    - Kommunistisches Bildungswesen, undated.; Ts Russia G389k. (Folder 172: 13)
      Consists chiefly of quotations from the Soviet press. Includes quotations on education
    - Ehe und Familie, undated.; Ts Russia G389e (Folder 172: 14)
    - Gesundheitswesen, undated.; Ts Russia G389g (Folder 172: 15)
    - Die Wohnungsfragen der UdSSR--Auszüge aus Sowjetbüchern und aus der Sowjetpresse, undated.; Ts Russia G389aus (Folder 172: 16)
    - Der Staatshaushalt der UdSSR in den Jahren 1918-1944--Allgemeine Bemerkungen zur Tabelle, undated.; Ts Russia G389 (Folder 172: 17)
    - Der Vernichtungskampf der Bolschewisten gegen die ukrainische Nationalkultur, circa 1944.; Ts Ukraine G389n (Folder 172: 18)
    - Das Schicksal der ukrainischen gelehrten in der Sowjetukraine, by Michael Antonowitsch, undated.; Ts Ukraine A635 (Folder 172: 19)
    - UHWR (Ukrainska Holowna Wyzwolna Rada) Ukrainischer Haupt-Befreiungsrat, circa 1944.; Ts Ukraine G389uk (Folder 172: 20)
    - Die Ukraine und der Bolschewismus, undated.; Ts Ukraine G389u (Folder 172: 21)
    - Judentum und Bolschewismus, undated.; Ts Jews G389 (Folder 172: 22)
    - Betr. Bericht über Lion Feuchtwanger, Institut zur wissenschaftlichen Erforschung der Sowjetunion, 1941.; TS France I59 (Folder 172: 23)
    - Generalfeldmarschall Paulus dem Nationalkomitee 'Freies Deutschland' beigetreten, 1944.; Ts Germany G389 (Folder 172: 24)
    - General Seydlitz spricht zu den deutschen Soldaten, 1944.; Ts Germany G389 (Folder 172: 25)
    - Zur Geschichte der Entstehung des Nationalen Komitees 'Freies Deutschland,' by Erich Weinert, 1943.; TS Germany G389 (Folder 172: 26)
    - Das Moskauer Komitee 'Freies Deutschland,', 1944.; Ts Germany G389 (Folder 172: 27)
    - "Une nouvelle menace sur l'Europe," Bulletin d'Information E.I.A., Entente Internationale Anticommuniste, 1944 October.; Ts Communis I61. Includes a translation into German, "Eine neue Drohung für Europa" (Folder 172: 28)
    - Zweite Besetzung der baltischen Staaten durch die Bolschewisten, undated.; Ts Baltic G389 (Folder 172: 29)
    - Die Entwicklung in Finnland nach Abschluss des Waffenstillstandsvertrages, by Carlo v. Kügelgen, circa 1944.; Ts Finland K95 (Folder 172: 30)
    - Wir wissen Bescheid! by Frh. V. Medem, undated.; Ts Communism M488 (Folder 172: 31)
    - Stellungnahme zur "Zusammenfassung über die Personal- und Materiallage der sowjet-russichen Wehrmacht,", 1944.; Ts Russia G389s (Folder 172: 32)
    - Materialsammlung zum Thema: "Krieg und Weltrevolution" aus Anlass der 27. Wiederkehr der bolschewistischen Revolution, v. 7, 1917 November.; Ts Communism G389m (Folder 172: 33)
    - Der Weg des Bolschewismus in England, Reichspropagandaleitung der NSDAP und des Reichspropagandaamtes der Deutschen Arbeitsfront, 1944.; Ts Great Britain N 277 (Folder 172: 34)
    - Auszüge aus dem Mitteilungsblatt des Einsatzstabes Rosenberg, Thema I: Wie sieht und beurteilt die Sowjetbevölkerung den Bolschewismus?, 1944.; Ts Russia G389ausz (Folder 172: 35)
    - Bolschewismus-Ungarn-Europa, undated.; Ts Communism G389b (Folder 172: 36)
    - Ungarn und der Bolschewismus, by Mergenthaler, undated.; Ts Hungary M559 (Folder 172: 37)
    - Die russischen Emigranten in Serbien und die Bolschewisten, undated.; Ts Serbia G389 (Folder 172: 38)
    - Das Problem der russischen, ukrainischen und weissruthenischen Staatenlosen, 1944.; Ts Russia G389p (Folder 172: 39)
    - Ernst Toller, 1919.; Ts Germany T651. Part photocopy, part typescript (Folder 172: 40)
    - Psychologische Kriegsvorbereitung, ciirca 1941.; Ts Russia G389ps (Folder 172: 41)
    - Die Beziehungen zwischen Mann und Frau in der Sowjetunion, S. S. Torskij, undated.; Ts Russia T698 (Folder 172: 42)
    - Das Verhör des Professors Platonow, Solovetskii, undated.; Ts Russia S689l. Translated from Russian (Folder 172: 43)
    - Die kommunistische Infiltration in Skandinavien, 1944.; Ts Scandinavia G389 (Folder 172: 44)
    - Biographical essay on Stalin, undated.; Ts Stalin B615. In Russian (Folder 172: 45)
    - Tovarishch Stalin: vozhd'narodov i otets trudiashchikhsia, circa 1943.; Ts Stalin A628. In Russian (Folder 172: 46)
    - Stalin reformator, circa 1943.; Ts Stalin A629. In Russian (Folder 172: 47)
    - Stalin reformator, circa 1943.; Ts Stalin A629a. In Ukrainian (Folder 172: 48)
    - Das Sowjetparadies, undated.; Ts Russia S681 (Folder 172: 49-50)
  - Unsorted material (Box 173-175)
- Group II, Monitoring Reports, 1933-1944.; (13 linear feet) (Box 176-206)
  Intelligence reports from diplomatic sources, monitored radio reports, and transcriptions of foreign newspaper articles.
  Arranged alphabetically in two subseries, (1) country or region, and (2) topic. Seven boxes of unsorted material (boxes 200-206) follow the two subseries
  - Country or region
    - Afghanistan, 1937 (File 176: 1)
    - Algeria, 1937-1938 (File 176: 2)
    - Angola, 1936 (File 176: 3)
    - Argentina, 1935-1939 (File 176: 4-16)
    - Australia, 1936-1939 (File 176: 17-18)
    - Austria, 1937-1939 (File 177: 1-10)
    - Balkans, 1939-1940 (File 177: 11)
    - Belgium, 1933-1939 (File 177: 12-19)
    - Bolivia, 1936-1939 (File 178: 1-2)
    - Brazil, 1935-1939 (File 178: 3-15)
    - Bulgaria, 1939-1940 (File 178: 16-23)
    - Chile, 1936-1939 (File 179: 1-5)
    - China, 1937-1944 (File 179: 6-17)
    - Colombia, 1937-1939 (File 179: 18)
    - Cuba, 1934-1939 (File 179: 19)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1936-1938 (File 180: 1-8)
    - Danzig, 1936-1938 (File 180: 9)
    - Denmark, 1936-1939 (File 180: 10-12)
    - East Africa, 1936-1938 (File 180: 13)
    - Egypt, 1936-1937 (File 180: 14)
    - France, 1938 (File 180: 15-17)
    - Germany, 1933-1937 (File 180: 18-20)
    - Germany, 1933-1937 (Box 181-183)
    - Hungary, 1937-1944 (File 184: 1-10)
    - Near East, 1940 (File 184: 11)
    - New Zealand, 1937-1938 (File 184: 12)
    - Norway, 1936-1939 (File 184: 13-14)